A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Department of Planning and Budget, Budget Operations Section, 1968-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Department of Planning and Budget, Budget Operations Section 1968-2005
The Library of Virginia
45195
9 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Virginia Department of Planning and Budget, Budget Operations Section, Records, Toni H. Jamison, Department of Planning and Budget, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 East Broad Street, Room 5005, Richmond, VA 23219, transferred 5 October 2010 and accessioned 7 October 2010.
Scope and Content
Contains correspondence, subject files and reports created and collected by the Virginia Department of Planning and Budget (DPB). The files iclude budget instruction memorandums from the DPB, reports on capital projects (renovation of Virginia State Library and Archives-now called the Patrick Henry Building; and Virginia Veterans Care Center), reports on Indigent Care costs and miscellaneous studies.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Records, 1968-2005
Contents List
- I. Records, 1968-2005., Extent: 9 cubic feet (9 boxes). (Box 1-9)
  Original order maintained
  - Miscellaneous Budget Instructions Memos from Budget Directors (Paul W. Timmreck, Karen F. Washabau and Robert W. Lauterberg), 1985-1996 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Budget Instruction Memos from Budget Directors (Robert W. Lauterberg and Scott D. Pattison), 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - DPB Memos from Director's Office and Budget Operations Secttion, 1999-June 2004 (Box 2)
  - Process for Executing Executive Memoranda and Executive Orders, 1984-1994 (Box 2)
  - Executive Orders, Governor Mark R. Warner, EO 1-83, 2002-2004 (incomplete) (Box 2)
  - File on "Agreement between and among The Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, The Virginia Museum Foundation and The Home for Needy Confederate Women, Inc.; EO 81 Providing for Continued Care for the Residents of the Home for Needy Confederate Women and the Transfer of the Home Property and Buildings, 1990 (Box 2)
  - History of the MCV Hospitals Building and Renovation Program, October 1974 (Box 3)
  - Budget Presentations by Karen F. Washabau, Director, Department of Planning and Budget, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Executive Summary, Renovation and Adaptive Reuse of the Virginia State Library and Archives Building and Space Needs Assessment for the Central Office Complex of the Virginia Department of Transportation, Boynton, Rothschild and Rowland Architects, September 1998 (1 of 3) (Box 3)
  - Basis of Design Narrative: Phase 1 - Schematic Design, Renovation and Adaptive Reuse of the Virginia State Library and Archives Building, Broad and Governor Streets, Richmond, Virginia for the Virginia Department of Transporataion, Capital Project 501-16211, Boynton, Rothschild and Rowland Architects, September 1998 (2 of 3) (Box 3)
  - Space Needs Assessment for the Central Office Complex of the Virginia Department of Transportation, Boynton, Rothschild and Rowland Architects, September 1998 (3 of 3) (Box 3)
  - Western Transportation Cooridor Study Coordination Report, Virginia Department of Transportation, October 1998 (Box 3)
  - Appendix M from the Budget Manual: Old Funding Policy for Institutions of Higher Education, 1968-1988 (Box 3)
  - Indigent Health Care at Medical College of Virginia Hospital, The University of Virginia Hospital and Medical College of Hampton Roads, 1985-1997
    - Indigent Care Reports, Agency 209, University of Virginia Medical Center, 1993-1995 (Box 4)
    - Indigent Care Reports, Agency 206 (MCV-VCU), 209 (University of Virginia) and 274 (Medical College of Hampton Roads), 1996-1997 (Box 4)
    - Indigent Care, Agencies, 2006, 2009 and 274, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Indigent Care, Virginia Apportionment of State Aid, Agencies 206, 2009 and 274, 1988-1995 (Box 4)
    - Indigent Care Cost Studies, 1986-1995 (Box 4)
    - Instructions for Indigent Care Cost Study, Ernst and Whinney, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Indigent Care Cost Reporting at MCV Hospital and the University of Virginia, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Indigent Health Care, 1990-1992 (Box 4)
  - Capital Outlay: Conversion to Electronic, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Six-Year Capital Outlay Working Papers, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Commonwealth Planning and Budgeting System (CPBS) Presentation Material, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Appropriation Transfer Report, May 1992-September 1996 and 1999-2003 (Box 5)
  - DPB Computing Environmental Study, 1995 (Box 6)
  - DPB Contracting Plan, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Appropriation/Allotment/FTE Employment Adjustment Request, 1992, 1998 (Box 6)
  - DPB Executive Agreement, 1984-1986 (Box 6)
  - Flextime Pilot Study, 1983, 1986 (Box 6)
  - DPB Information Technology Resources Plan, 1994 (Box 6)
  - DPB Information Services Standards Manual, 1994 (Box 6)
  - DPB International Projects (Box 6)
  - DPB Internship Program, 1990, 1993, 1997 (Box 6)
  - DPB Photo (Staff) with Governor Gilmore, 1998 (Box 6)
  - DPB Staff Survey, 1994 (Box 6)
  - DPB Training, Miscellaneous Topics, 1987-2005 (Box 6)
  - Capital Budget Process, 1987 (Box 7)
  - VS Spreadsheet System, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Performance Budgeting Process, Virginia, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Performance Measures, General, 1993, 1996 and 1997 (Box 7)
  - Performance Measures Training, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Federal Budget Reports, 1991, 1993, 1997 and 2001 (Box 7)
  - Revenue Bond Bill Preparation, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Commonwealth Performance Advisory Management Committee, 2000-2002 (Box 8)
  - Compacts of Virginia, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Debt Capacity Advisory Committee Reports, 1998-2000 (Box 8)
  - Debt Financing in Virginia, Senate Finance Committee, 1989 (Box 8)
  - An Assessment of Debt Management in Virginia, prepared by Secretary of Finance, 1990 and 1991 (Box 8)
  - The State of the Commonwealth's Debt, a Report to Governor Allen, Secretary of Finance, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Debt: A Re-Examination of the Use(s) of Lottery Profits, Report of the Governor to the General Assembly, 1992 and 1993 (Box 8)
  - Delegation of Authority, 1987-1993 (Box 8)
  - Federal Funds Cash Management Agreement, 1984-1993 (Box 8)
  - Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, State Plan of Operation, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Insurance: Health Forecasting Process and Methodologies for the State Employee Health Fund, Report to the Commonwealth of Virginia, Watson Wyatt Worldwide, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Intergovernmental Review System, Section 89 of the Internal Revenue Code, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Land Acquisition Study, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Constitutional Amendment to Limit State Government, SJR 28, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Performance Management Advisory Committee, Annual Report, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Personnel: Management of the Commonwealth's Workforce, Drafts, Vols. 1 and 2, Joint Commission on Management of the Commonwealth Workforce, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Population Projections: HCA Health Services of Virginia vs. Paul W. Timmreck, re Certificate of Need for Hospital in Northern Virginia (case dismissed), 1987 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Veterans Care Center, History, Study Proposal and Miscellaneous Files, 1989-2002 (Box 9)
  - Study: The Governor's Regulatory Reform Advisory Board, Final Report, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Study: Findings by the Task Force Examining Optional Retirement Plans for Faculty of Institutions of Higher Education, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Study: Organizational Structure for the Virginia Geographic Information Network, 1995 (Box 9)
  - The Transition to Digital Television of Virginia's Public Television Stations, 1999 (Box 9)